Are you familiar with Robert House?
Are you asking me to spy
on the wealthiest man in America?
Not spy on him.
Help!
Folks in them outfits
don't deserve savin'.
Let her go!
Give me the stimpak.
I only have one.
Help me!
Please!
She'll die without it.
Golden rule. motherfucker.
I am nothing like you.
We'll get you home to your people.
The axis of power
has shifted in the Brotherhood.
Holy fuck!
How many of those can you make?
More than all of human history
could ever consume.
Liaison from the Commonwealth.
I understand we're discussing
a civil war.
Just so you know...
I am nice.
- Oh! Oh.
- No...
Thaddeus...
I-I think you might be a ghoul.
Oh. no!
Way to use those little hands. Lois.
Keep it up.
Thanks. boss.
Bobby! Hey!
I see your eyes closing over there.
You know what happens
when you fall asleep on the job?
Nothing good. that's for sure.
- Mm-hm.
- Yep.
Come on. gang.
we're only 12 hours into this shift!
We got 10 more to go!
- Okay?
Perry. you know what?
Try it without the gloves.
The meat on your palms.
gonna give you a better grip.
Just...  get in there.
- It's gonna hurt a little bit. but...
I did it!
Keep it up and you'll have big.
gross. calloused hands in no time.
- Yes. sir!
Trudy!
Why aren't you makin' money for me?
Lois called me a mean name.
Lois. is that true?
She said I look like a ghoul.
Well. there's nothing wrong with
being a ghoul. except you're not.
I'm a ghoul.
Perry over there.
now. well. that's a ghoul.
Disgusting! Eech!
I think this might be
a good reminder for everybody.
Hey. hey. listen up!
Little break here real quick. everybody.
Okay.
Reminder. we're all really.
really lucky to be here.
Believe me.
I have seen some shit out there.
But here. we got it made.
We got a roof over our heads.
a very well-defended perimeter.
- What about water?
- Just drink the soda. alright?
You-- you know what the best part
about this place is?
Nobody wakes you up
in the morning to do push-ups
or makes you carry around
a big old bag all the time.
All in all. I'd say life's pretty good.
What do we always say?
Most kids are dead by this age!
Okay. back to work.
Keep up!
Keep moving!
You lost your Legionary.
Please. Please. Please. Pl--
The enemy horde has been
relocating their artillery farther north.
So. to counterbalance.
we need to relocate ours as well.
Ave. profligate.
Yes.
Hi. sir.
How dare you address the great Caesar?
"Kai-sar"? You...
Do-- do you mean Caesar?
I believe Kaisers were German.
and you guys
have more of a Roman theme. so...
I-- I think it's Caesar.
This is the one.
- Sir. please. Um. I see that this is a...
um... work camp.
- And if I may. I'm a very--
- Shh.
We're negotiating the rights
to your prima noctis.
Prima noctis?
Okay. First of all. shame on you.
That is awful.
And secondly. prima noctis
isn't even a Roman tradition.
It's from the Middle Ages.
They were just nasty people
borrowing a Latin phrase.
And as much as I want
to respect your traditions...
there is a line to all that.
which I think we have found.
And you should know
that I am not even a virgin.
- And that's not including
all of the cousin stuff I did. which is
at least a page or two on my resume.
So. looks like we're out of options.
If you don't mind me saying.
it seems like you guys
might have lost your way out here.
I wouldn't expect a profligate
like you to understand.
- We're at war.
- With who?
The New California Republic.
The Khans. The Brotherhood.
But first. we must conquer
the unrepentant members
of Caesar's Legion.
Over there.
All hail Caesar!
There's two Caesars?
The great founder of this Empire. he died.
We've been at war ever since
over who should be his heir.
He wrote down the name of his successor.
He placed it into his divine pocket.
But every time we try to retrieve it.
the false Caesar and his followers.
they shoot at us.
We are at a stalemate.
I may be able to help you.
I have experience with family counseling.
and sometimes conflict resolution...
it's easier than you think.
Oh. geez.
Excuse me!
This isn't Rome. okay? This is America!
- Is it?
- Yeah. it is.
At least according to all the maps.
Maps drawn by the dead.
All that remains of America
is the overwhelming
evidence of its failure.
Now. if you'll excuse me.
we have a war to win.
You know. speaking as someone
who's seen upwards of 15 different movies.
if you think everyone else is the bad guy.
chances are. you're the bad guy.
But "good" is not a meaningful vector
in history.
Only strength.
Ah!
Yeah. well...
How 'bout a boat that's not a boat.
You know what I mean?
Of course. you do.
You take out one plank...
boat's the same as it ever was.
It's just got a-- a hole in it.
that's all.
You take out a-- a lot of planks...
and all of a sudden.
you gotta ask yourself...
...what-- what the fuck am I looking at?
This ain't no boat.
It's just a-- a pile of wood. man.
It's just a fuckin' pile of wood.
I don't know
what I'm tellin' you all this for.
I know you already know all this.
It's just been a while...
since I had someone worth talkin' to.
That's all.
You okay?
Yeah. I. uh...
I just... I-I can't seem to get
Janey's teddy into the Keepsake Box.
For the Vault.
I just hate leaving
anything behind. you know?
Well. we may not have to. right?
Well. I've gotta go
to this thing for Charlie.
Okay.
What do you know about Robert House?
All I heard is that he's building
some kind of weapons system in Vegas.
Our intel thinks it's connected
to what you heard Barb talking about.
Your intel?
It's blueprints and a bunch
of phone records.
What else am I supposed to call that?
Intel. I guess.
Well. do you know what your boss
wants me to do to him?
Mm.
- I didn't know.
Look. I wanna help.
I'll do whatever I can.
But there's gotta be another way.
Look where we are. Coop.
Half the guys in here have killed people.
Maybe not the right ones.
Robert House is just one person.
My name is Diane Welch.
congresswoman
for the District of Glendale.
And if you've never heard of me.
it's probably because
I'm the only sitting congressperson
in this administration to have
refused corporate funding.
So. while I may not be able
to afford TV spots and billboards.
I don't think America can afford
any more corporate influence
in Washington.
- Get on with it.
Okay.
Well. today isn't about me.
it's about you and the sacrifices
you've made for this great nation.
As a friend to our brothers
and sisters in the armed forces.
it is my honor to award...
Um. let me just find my card here.
- Oh.
The story of today's first honoree
is just...
I'm gonna go hit the head.
...wonderful.
if I can find my notes.
You getting any awards tonight?
Um. no.
No. no. I'm just here for an old friend.
- Corporal Charlie Whiteknife.
Yeah. Yeah. Charlie.
Rumor has it. he's a bit of a pinko.
Is that right?
I wouldn't know about that.
And what about you. Mr. Howard?
What about me?
Oh. Cooper Howard?
American veteran?
Star of the silver screen?
Pinko?
Don't believe everything you read.
Oh. don't get me wrong.
I sympathize with the pinko point of view.
Yeah.
They have grievances
with traditional institutions.
Entirely justified. if you ask me.
I didn't ask you.
It's their solution to the problem.
Oh. Here.
You back a body into a corner.
they're liable to try anything.
You back billions of bodies
into a corner at the same time...
Tsk.
Everyone trying to solve the same problem
at the same time
with a multitude of solutions.
Messy. messy. hm?
I take it you're not a vet.
What gave me away?
Because a vet would know better
than to talk politics
when a man has his dick in his hand.
'Til next time. Mr. Howard.
The Codex is clear
about chain of command.
We mustn't squander this opportunity.
I told you. We're out.
I acknowledge the arrival of the Paladin
from the Commonwealth
complicates the issue. but--
I'm not interested
in fighting a rebellion. Quintus.
But the Brotherhood
began as an act of rebellion.
Before the war. an ordinary captain
was sent to a research center
in California.
Roger Maxson.
And when he saw
what they were doing there...
depraved experiments on human subjects.
well. then. Roger Maxson
had to ask himself.
who did he serve?
His God?
Or his government?
He chose his God.
He shot the scientists.
He shot the people who tried to stop him.
His government had defied God.
and for that. he defied his government.
But he wasn't punished.
He was saved.
So that he could found our noble order.
If our rebellion is righteous...
the way will be paved for us.
I told you.
I don't go in for the religious stuff.
Give the Cold Fusion relic
to the Commonwealth.
- Oh...
My lord...
this Xander guy...
I could just kill him.
Well. that's what we do here. Isn't it?
Behold. the dimness of the sword.
We just lost the alliance.
If we kill Xander.
the envoy from the Commonwealth.
it will be war.
And without the support
of the other chapters.
it will end with all our heads on spikes.
Yes. my lord.
but if our cause is righteous--
I have no need for the thoughts
of a sword!
Leave.
Must I repeat myself?
No. my lord.
There he is.
What do you want?
Well. my arrival seems to have
put a damper on the conversation.
Lift with your knees!
Your Clerics won't even look at me.
You guys have a lot of Clerics.
you know that?
Yeah. I guess we do.
Yeah. scurrying around everywhere
like little cockroaches.
Right?
I mean. we have Clerics
back at the Commonwealth.
They're just not. like.
in charge. you know?
And I know every chapter
of the Brotherhood
is a little different. but this one...
...sucks. No offense.
I shouldn't be talking to you.
Chain of command.
Good man. See?
That's a soldier for you.
Your Elder Cleric is about
to make a mistake.
The Brotherhood that you believe in.
that I believe in?
We are the last bastion
of order in this country.
We are a bulwark against chaos.
If you ask me. fomenting a rebellion
sounds a lot like chaos.
You know. back East.
it's guys like us who call the shots.
People who put their ass on the line.
That is foundational
to the Brotherhood ethos.
Your Clerics? What do they do?
Stand around. give speeches.
We are the ones who bleed.
What do you want me to do about it?
Just talk to me.
You know. this isn't the first time
that the Brotherhood
has been on the verge of civil war.
But if us soldiers figure something out.
it won't be the first time that
cooler heads have prevailed.
What do you say?
Yeah. let's talk.
Hot dog.
Well. Miss Lucy...
how's that golden rule
workin' out for you now?
What the fuck?
Kinda looks like we got ourselves
a civil war.
Well. shit.
What you think. dog?
What?
Don't look at me like that.
I don't like her either.
- But we gonna need her down the line.
I ain't going up against
two Legions in one afternoon.
We need some help.
And this is about
the best place to get it.
Used to be. anyway.
H-Howdy. p-p-p-p-p-pardner!
Is that you. Victor?
V-V-Victor. That sure does sound familiar.
Well. dagnabbit. spent the last ten years
thinkin' I was a soda machine.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Well. b-b-beats me. pardner.
Someone did a number on my numbers.
Memory's all jimble-jambled.
Is that right?
Well. I gotta save a dipshit Vaultie
from the Legion.
Came here hopin' to get
some help from the NCR.
N-N-N-NCR? I ain't seen 'em.
Who's running these parts these days?
Well you know how it is around here.
The NCR and the Legion goin' at each other
like cats and dogs.
Though now. we got the Legion fightin'
the Legion like cats and dogs. too.
Is that so?
But you know what they say in Vegas.
Everyone's a winner. Eventually.
The same goes for losing.
in my experience.
Except for one man.
The man that built you.
Where's Robert House?
He's gone.
He had all the money in the world.
But all he really wanted
was to live forever.
Life just ain't fair. I guess.
Well. typically. I would agree.
But you should know better than anyone
that House had a knack for plannin' ahead.
Oh. he had plans. alright.
But he needed the Cold Fusion doodad
from before the war.
Didn't you have somethin'
to do with all that?
Way back when?
Oh. you're leavin' already?
Ain't nobody around to keep
poor Victor company these days.
Just them Rangers up in the hills.
Rangers in the hills?
Well. you know how it is.
The NCR and the Legion.
they can't stop fightin'.
Like c-c-c-cats and d-dogs.
Much obliged. Victor.
Well. I'll be seein' you!
I'm sure you will.
We need a pilot.
And let someone else have all the fun?
- Let's go!
- Well. I should grab my--
You don't need your Armor.
I got a spare you could use.
They give you spares?
Motion assist servos.
It's nice.
Yeah. I don't know anything
about any of that shit. man.
I just know how to kick ass in it.
you know?
Alright.
You ever flown one of these?
Oh. no. no.
Here. let me give you control right now.
Hold on to it.
- No. no!
- Flip the switch-- you sure? Yeah?
- No!
- Okay.
You gotta try it.
Soon.
Hey. Maximus. can we just
be hard dick for a second?
Oh. yeah.
Unless your guy Quintus
gives me that relic.
you and me are going to be
on the front line
shooting at each other soon.
And I know you're very good. but trust me.
you don't want that heat.
And I don't know. I'm just thinking.
if I go home with the relic.
there's no bloodshed. you know?
I'll be honest with you. man.
We are really up against it back home.
Without that relic you found.
we risk losing the Commonwealth.
And if the Commonwealth falls...
civilization won't last much longer.
What do you mean. "won't last"?
- I mean. look at it out here.
- It can get worse.
Trust me.
Just think about it. that's all.
I trust your judgment. Maximus.
So should you.
- Oh. fuck yeah!
- What is it?
- Power signatures in a complex nearby.
Looks like unauthorized
automated activity.
You're 2.000 miles away from home.
What do you care about a couple
of robots in the desert?
We're the Brotherhood of Steel.
We keep the Wasteland safe.
This is what we do!
This is what we get to do!
- Oh. here it is.
Hot dog!
C'mon!
Yeah!
Hot dog.
Oh. I know.
Huh.
Captain Rodriguez
of the New California Republic!
Well. I can see your salutations
haven't changed.
Fucker!
Stop! Don't hurt 'im!
Why not?
This ghoul and the NCR go way back.
Gotta be ready.
Gotta be ready. They're coming any day.
We gotta be ready. Any day now.
If I may...
New California Republic
may wanna drop the word "New."
'cause y'all lookin' dusty as hell.
Where is everybody?
Up here. it's just us.
We've been cut off from reinforcements
for more than a decade.
They're comin'.
Guess. uh. time takes a toll
on some more than others.
When Shady Sands fell.
we had a battalion out east.
- We could still get to them.
- Shady Sands?
You do know that
was over 20 years ago. right?
Legion has us boxed in.
We've lost touch with our battalion.
Please. help us contact them.
Let our people know we're still out here.
What's so funny?
I'm in a minor predicament.
I came to the NCR looking for help
based on the cozy-ass assumption
that the good guys would prevail
in the great state of Nevada.
- We're winning the war.
- We are.
Well. if this is winnin'.
I would hate to see
what losin' looks like.
Please.
The stuff we fight for...
clean water. schools...
rights for folks like you...
story has it. you used to believe
in those things. too.
Please. help us. before we're captured.
Ain't nobody comin'.
'Cause there ain't nobody left.
Little piece of advice that's helped me
sleep at night over the years.
When something's dead.
it's usually because it deserved to die.
Alright. bro. Let's do this.
In here.
Come on. Max.
I'm-- I'm coming.
Hold up.
Halt! Display your credentials!
Greetings. visitor!
Would you prefer a neck
or foot massage today?
There will be no massage!
I-I-Identification is--
Please remove your clothing
and apply a complimentary towel.
Cancel massage
p-p-p-protocol immediately! Intruder!
Massage protocol activated!
Activating version...
Xander?
Intruder!
Prepare to be-be neutralized.
Relaxation imminent!
Get back!
Ah!
Ha. ha. fuck yeah!
You ever see one of these?
What is that?
Watch this.
Come on. you big metallic piece o' shit!
Yeah!
Ha. ha. ha. yeah!
Suck on this!
Ooh!
That's all you got?
Hey. Xander. you okay?
Suck it!
Come on.
Hey. Max! You want a piece of this?
Oh. hell yeah.
Over here. you big bag of bolts.
Come on. dickhead!
- Hoo-hoo! Nice one!
- Yay!
- Right?
- Boom!
Yeah. Gee whiz. that felt good.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
You want a turn with this?
Wow. D-- Thank you.
Hot dog.
"Ah-way."
Or whatever the fuck
y'all say to each other.
You claim to have information for Caesar.
Well. I understand
that the Legion ain't fans
of the linear progression of time...
or the soft "C." for that matter.
But I bet you still understand
cause and effect.
Now. I give you something you want.
And. well. you give me something I want.
Or we can put you up on a cross
until you give us what we want.
Well. yeah. you could do that.
Or you could exterminate the last holdout
of the New California Republic.
I can tell you where they're hidin'.
Now. remember.
these are the 45s.
They're hard as hell to walk in.
And this Power Armor's
so goddamn hot from the fires
that it's melting the snow
beneath my feet.
And I'm dragging this guy. you know.
just dragging him
through the mud and the slush.
And I don't know if this
poor damn grunt is dead or alive.
So. the first chance I get.
I take cover. take a knee.
open up that visor.
And who do I see staring right back at me?
It's Cooper Howard.
- That's right.
You know what he said to me?
Coop.
You remember?
Uh. "How do I look?"
That's a lie. ladies and gentlemen.
That is a lie.
I mean. the movie star Cooper Howard.
he probably would have said that.
But the man I was looking at...
he looked up at me and he said.
"How are the others?"
Nearly burnt alive...
and he was worried about our squad.
Fuckin' Marines. huh?
We like to tell stories
about what we did out there.
Yeah. not all of them. anyways.
Some of them we can't tell.
But the ones we do tell...
we tell 'em to make us feel good
about what we did.
To give us hope that it was all
for the right reasons.
But we're just Marines.
We don't get the privilege of knowing.
We just had to go off
of what they told us.
They told us that it was all
on the line...
fate of the whole free world.
With the stakes stacked that high...
we didn't get much choice. did we?
And I guarantee you.
the guys on the other side
got told the same shit.
Tonight. we bury
the New California Republic!
At the end of the day.
we just gotta hope
that we bet on the right side.
The side that protects
the people you love.
Because if it did...
I guess that's worth doing
pretty much anything.
Even something bad.
Anyway. uh. thank you
for the potato salad.
Um. it was good seeing all of you.
and. uh. thank you.
Uh. wait.
You can't leave without your award.
It's a. um. commemorative lighter.
So. congratulations. Corporal.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
Don't thank me yet.
This is for you.
They gave that to me for saving a man.
Not for killing the three
it took to do it.
Maybe this was a mistake.
Why? What did you do?
I don't know. Maybe somethin' good.
Or maybe somethin' stupid.
Ha-ha. gotcha!
On your feet!
Oh. no. No.
Aw. it's just a baby abomination!
Hey. buddy.
Where are your friends?
Where there's one. there's always another.
Alright. I know there's more of you here.
so you better come on out.
Don't worry. We're not going to hurt you.
Aw. good little ones.
Oh. jackpot.
Were you guys playing hide-and-seek?
I love that game.
It's okay. it's okay.
You're okay.
Yeah. you're all okay.
Alright. I'm gonna split you up
into two groups. okay?
If you have smooth skin.
walk over to this side of the table.
Wrinkles. stay right here
in front of me. okay?
Hey. wait. Xander? Xander.
Alright. smooth skins. close your eyes.
Please. stop.
Hi! Hello!
Oh. if I may.
I'm the manager here.
and. uh. I just ask you...
please don't do what you're about to do.
I know I don't have a lot
of leverage here or anything.
but. you know. they're just...
they're just kids.
So. who cares. right?
They're not kids. They're abominations.
And so are you.
But they are kids.
Xander. Xander. come on. man. we don't...
- No.
- Please. Xander. please stop!
The Codex is clear on this.
And without the rules. where are we?
Fuck the Codex. Xander! Listen to me!
No. No. no. no. No. no. no!
- Hot dog!
- Stop. Xander!
- No. no. no. no. no. no. no!
- Wait!
No! No!
Hey. man.
Hey.
Uh... what you been up to?
I think I just started a war.
Okay.
Yeah. well. um.
I'm the floor manager here.
So. it sounds like we both
got a lot going on right now.
Yeah.